# **CARLOS NETO**

## **DEVOPS ENGINEER**

% www.carlosneto.dev

in linkedin.com/in/c-neto/

github.com/c-neto

★ credly.com/c-neto/badges

**♀** Brazil - São Paulo

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

Dedicated and self-motivated IT professional with a strong commitment to continuous learning and a deep sense of ownership.

Proficient in a range of technical skills including programming, documentation, and DevOps. Specialized in Python programming and well-versed in Amazon Web Services, with a primary focus on system provisioning, creating automation scripts, and managing log pipelines and observability stacks.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **DevOps Engineer**

# Trustly | Open Banking Platform

Movember 2021 - Current

Remote

I work on a global Account-to-Account Open Banking System, where my primary responsibilities encompass scripting, cloud component optimization, and log pipeline creation. My core tasks include:

- Crafting automation scripts using Python and Bash.
- Managing a massive OpenSearch cluster, including Cluster configuration, RBAC, and Template tuning.
- Developing and maintaining Logstash log pipelines.
- Optimizing AWS resources focuses on performance and security.
- Kubernetes operating, troubleshooting, and optimization.
- Knowledge Base documentation.

## Software Developer

## Fotosensores | Speed Camera Systems

April, 2018 - October, 2021

**♀** On-site

I focus on meeting in-house infrastructure needs, primarily within a regional Speed Camera System. My key responsibilities include:

- Developing Python microservices, scripts, and integrations.
- Managing GitLab CI/CD pipelines.
- Setting up monitoring with Zabbix, Prometheus, and Grafana.
- Developing Log Pipelines with Rsyslog, Loki, and Grafana.
- Handling Linux server and RPM packaging (CentOs-based).
- Knowledge Base documentation.

#### **PROJECTS**

- OpenSearch Security and Monitoring (Trustly): Implemented robust monitoring (Prometheus + Grafana), and security best practices, including the Principle of Least Privilege, and Defense-in-Depth;
- **SFTP Cluster (Trustly)**: Implemented a highly available SFTP server using Ansible for user setup and Kubernetes for deployment;
- Image Transmissions Module (Fotosensores): Developed a module for speed camera systems that securely transmits vehicle images with data integrity and cryptography;
- Speed Camera Monitoring System (Fotosensores): Created a web-based system for monitoring and observing components of the speed camera system.

## **EDUCATION**

Analisys and Development System (High-Education)

**FATEC - São José dos Campos** 

## July 2016 - July 2019

Computer Network (Full-Certified)
ETEC - Cônego José Bento

Industrial Automation (Full-Certified)
ITJ - Instituto de Tecnologia de Jacareí

High February 2013 - December 2015

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect AWS;
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner AWS;
- GitHub Actions GitHub;
- GitLab Certified Associate Gitlab Inc;
- Python Formation Certified Alura;
- Fluent Python Book.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming

Python Bash

Cloud

AWS

· Observability and Monitoring

OpenSearch ELK Stack Grafana

Prometheus Rsyslog Zabbix Loki

CI/CD and GitOps

GitLab Github TravisCI ArgoCD

Containers Orchestration

Kubernetes Docker-Compose

• Infrastructure as a Code

Ansible Terraform

Messaging and Reverse Proxy

RabbitMQ ZeroMQ SQS Redis